So the brain is controlled through the Spirit.
สมองถูกควบคุมโดยจิตวิญญาน
How?
อย่างไร
That around the heart there are seven auras
รอบๆหัวใจมี 7 ออร่า
which can be multiplied into any number,
ซึ่งสามารถทวึคูณเป็นหลายๆจำนวน
seven raised to power sixteen hundred,
จาก 7 เพิ่มขึ้นเปน 1,600
which are the ones which watch the seven chakras,
ซึ่งหนึ่งในนั้นเฝ้ามองจักราทั้งเจ็ด
raised to power sixteen hundred - sixteen thousand, sorry.
ยกพลังขึ้นเป็น 1,600 - 16,000
Now this Spirit is watching through this aura.
ขณะนี้ จิตวิญญานเฝ้ามองผ่านออร่านี้
Watching, I am again saying "watching"
เฝ้ามอง แม่ขอพูดอีกตรั้ง "เฝ้ามอง"
through this aura.
ผ่านออร่านี้
This aura is watching
ออร่านี้กำลังเฝ้ามอง
the behavior of your seven centers in your brain.
พฤติกรรมของศูนย์กลางทั้งเจ็ดในสมองของคุณ
Is also watching all the nerves
เฝ้ามองเส้นประสาททั้งหมดด้วย
that are working in the brain
ว่ากำลังทำงานในสมอง
"watching", again.
เฝ้าดูอีกแล้ว
But when you bring the Spirit into your brain,
แต่เมื่อคุณนำจิตวิญญานเข้าไปในสมองของคุณ
then you go two steps ahead,
แล้วคุณก็ไปข้างหน้าอีก 2 ขั้นตอน
because when your Kundalini rises,
เพราะเมื่อกุณฑาลิณีของคุณตื่นชึ้น
She touches the Sadashiva
เธอสัมผัสกับ Sadashiva
and Sadashiva informs the Spirit.
และ Sadashiva ก็ให้ข้อมูลกับจิตวิญญาน
Informs in the sense - reflects in the Spirit.
ให้ข้อมูลในความรู้สึก-สะท้อนในจิตวิญญาน
So that's the first state where the watching auras
ดังนั้นในสภาวะแรกที่ ออร่าเฝ้าดู
start communicating
เริ่มสื่อสาร
through your different chakras
ผ่านจักราที่แตกต่างออกไป
in the brain
ในสมอง
and integrating it.
และรวบรวมมัน
But when you bring your Spirit to your brain
แต่เมื่อคุณนำจิตวิญญานเข้าไปในสมอง
this is the second state.
นี่เป็นสภาวะที่ 2
Then you really become self-realized,
แล้วคุณก็เกิดรู้แจ้งด้วยตนเองจริงๆ
in the full way,
แบบเต็มหนทาง
because then your Self, that is the Spirit,
แล้วตัวคุณซึ่งก็คือจิตวิญญาน
becomes your brain.
กลายเป็นสมองของคุณ
Action is very dynamic, it opens then,
การกระทำแบบเปลี่ยนแปลงต่อเนื่อง ได้เปิดออกแล้ว
the fifth dimension in the human being.
มิติที่ 5 ของการเป็นมนุษย์ชาติ
First when your become realized, collectively conscious,
อย่างแรกเมื่อคุณตระหนักรู้,รวบรวมสติ
and start raising the Kundalini,
และเริ่มปลุกพลังกุณฑาลิณี
you are in, you cross the fourth dimension.
คุณอยู่ใน , คุณผ่านมิติที่ 4
But when your Spirit comes into your brain,
แต่เมื่อจิตวิญญานของคุณเข้าใปในสมอง
then you become the fifth dimension
คุณจะกลายเป็นมิติที่ 5
means, you become the doer.
หมายความว่า คุณจะเป็นผู้กระทำอย่างจริงจัง
Our brain, now, for example says, "All right,
สมองของเราตอนนี้ ยกตัวอย่างเวลาพูดว่า "เอาหละ
lift this thing up." So you touch it with your hand,
ยกสิ่งนี้ขึ้น" คุณสัมผัสสิ่งนี้ด้วยมือของคุณ
you lift it up. You are the doer.
คุณยกมันขึ้น คุณคือผู้กระทำ
But when the brain becomes the Spirit,
แต่เมื่อสมองของคุณเป็นจิตวิญญาน
the Spirit is the doer,
จิตวิญญานเป็นผู้กระทำ
and when Spirit is the doer,
และเมื่อจิตวิญญานเป็นผู้กระทำ
then you become a complete Shiva - self-realized.
แล้วคุณกลายเป็น พระศิวะตระหนักรู้ด้วยตนเองอย่างสมบูรณ์แบบ
In that state,
ในสภาวะนั้น
if you get angry, you are not attached.
ถ้าคุณโกรธ คุณไม่ถูกเชื่อมต่อ
You are not an attached person to anything whatsoever.
คุณเป็นบุคคลที่ไม่ถูกเชื่อมต่อกับอะไรเลย
If you possess anything, you are not attached.
ถ้าคุณครอบงำบางสิ่ง คุณจะไม่ถูกเชื่อมต่อ
You cannot attach, because Spirit is detachment,
คุณไม่สามารถเชื่อมต่อ เพราะว่าจิตวิญญานแยกออก
complete detachment.
แยกออกโดยสมบูรณ์
You don't bother about any attachments whatsoever.
คุณไม่ต้องกังวลเกี่ยวกับการเชื่อมต่อใดๆ
Even for a second, you are not attached.
แม้ว่า ครั้งที่ 2 คุณไม่ถูกเชื่อมต่อ
Now I would say,
ตอนนี้แม่พูดว่า
to understand the detachment of Spirit,
เพื่อความเข้าใจเรื่องการแยกออกของจิตวิญญาน
we should study ourselves very well, clearly.
เราต้องศีกษาตัวเราเองอย่างดีมาก และชัดเจน
How are we attached?
เราจะเชื่อมต่อได้อย่างไร
We are attached, firstly, by our brain,
เราถูกเขื่อมต่อ อย่างแรก โดยสมองของเรา
mostly by our brain,
ส่วนใหญ่โดยสมองของเรา
because all our conditionings are in our brain
เพราะว่าเงื่อนไขทั้งหมดของเรา อยู่ในสมองของเรา
and all our ego is also in our brain.
และอัตตาของเราก็อยู่ในสมองของเราด้วย
So all emotional attachments
ดังนั้นการเชื่อมต่อกับอารมภ์ทั้งหมด
are through our brain
จะผ่านสมองของเรา
and all our egoistical attachments also are through our brain.
และการเชื่องต่อกับอัตตาของเราทั้งหมด ก็ผ่านสมองของเราด้วย
That's why it is said that after Realization one must try
นั่นหละทำไมถึงพูดว่า หลังจากตระหนักรู้ แต่ละท่านต้องพยายาม
to practice the Shiva Tattwa
ฝึกฝนสัจธรรมของพระศิวะ
by practicing detachment.
โดยฝึกฝนการแยกออก
Now how do you practice this detachment?
ตอนนึ้ คุณฝึกการแยกออกนี้อย่างไร
In the practice of Sahaja Yoga,
ในการฝึกของสหจะโยคะ
if you have to rise higher
ถ้าคุณได้ขึ้นสูงขึ้น
you have to improve your own instrument
คุณต้องพัฒนาเครื่องมือของคุณเอง
and not the instrument of others.
และไม่ใช่เครื่องมือของคนอื่น
This is one thing one should know, for definite.
นี่คือสิ่งที่แต่ละคนควรจะรู้อย่างชัดเจน
Now, you just watch your attention. Where is it going.
ตอนนี้ คุณแค่เฝ้าดูความสนใจของคุณ ว่ากำลังไปที่ไหน
Watch yourself.
เฝ้าดูตัวคุณเอง
As soon as you'll start watching yourself, your attention,
เร็วที่สุดที่คุณเริ่มเฝ้าดูตัวเอง ดูความสนใจของคุณ
you'll become more identified with your Spirit.
คุณจะสามารถวิเคราะห์จิตวิญญานของคุณได้มากขึ้น
Because if you have to watch your attention,
เพราะ ถ้าคุณต้องเฝ้าดูความสนใจของคุณ
you will have to be your Spirit, otherwise how will you watch it?
คุณจะต้องกลายเป็นจิตวิญญานของคุณ ไม่งั้นคุณจะดูเฝ้าดูมันอย่างไร
So now see where is your attention going.
ดังนั้นตอนนี้ ดูว่าความสนใจของคุณไปอยู่ที่ไหน
First, the attachment is, in all gross ways, to your body.
อย่างแรก การเชื่อมต่อคือ อยู่ทุกทางที่มาหาตัวคุณ
So we see Shiva - there's no attachment to His body.
ดังนั้นเราเห็นพระศิวะ ไม่มีการเชื่อมต่อมาหาตัวท่าน
He sleeps anywhere.
ท่านหลับทุกที่
He goes to the cemeteries and sleeps there,
ท่านไปที่สุสานและหลับที่นั่น
because He's not attached.
เพราะท่านไม่มีการเชื่อมต่อ
He can never be caught up by any bhoots or anything,
ท่านไม่สามารถถูกจับโดยพวกผีปีศาจหรือสิ่งต่างๆ
nothing of the kind. He is detached.
ไม่มีสิ่งเหล่านั้น ท่านแยกออก
The detachment is to be watched
สิ่งที่แยกออกถูกเฝ้าดู
and seen through your own attachments.
และมองเห็นผ่าน สิ่งที่เชื่อมต่อของคุณเอง
Now, because you are realized souls,
ตอนนี้ เพราะว่าคุณตะหนักถึงวิญญาน
not yet the Spirit, has not come into your brain of course,
ยังไม่ใช่จิควิญญาน ไม่เข้ามาในสมองแน่นอน
but still you are realized souls.
แต่คุณยังเป็นวิญญานตระหนักรู้
So what you can do is
ดังนั้นอะไรที่คุณควรทำคือ
at least to watch your attention, you can do that.
อย่างน้อยที่สุด เฝ้าดูความสนใจของคุณ คุณสามารถทำอย่างนั้น
You can watch your attention very clearly
คุณสามารถเฝ้าดูความสนใจของคุณอย่างชัดเจนมาก
by seeing where your attention is going.
โดยดูว่า ความสนใจของคุณไปที่ไหน
And then, controlling your attention, also, you can do.
และแล้วควบคุมความสนใจของคุณ คุณสามารถทำได้ด้วย
Very simple.
ง่ายมาก
To control your attention you have to just
ตวบคุมความสนใจของคุณ คุณแค่
remove your attention from this to that.
ย้ายความสนใจของคุณจากนี่ไปนั้น
Try to change your priorities,
พยายามเปลี่ยนระดับความสำคัญ
all this has to be done now,
ทั้งหมดนี้ต้องทำเวลานี้
after Realization - a complete detachment.
หลังจากตระหนักรู้  การแยกออกที่สมบูรณ์แบบ